Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we're traveling
a little bit and we need
to book a hotel room.
That's right so today
we're going to learn
all the words and
phrases that will help you
talk to the receptionist in
order to book a hotel room.
Let's check out our dialogue.
Madison Swedes, how may I help you?
Yes, I am calling for
Mexico, I will be in
town next week and would like
to know if you have availability.
Okay ma'am, can you tell me
the dates you expect to check in?
Yes, July 9, I will be there for 7 nights.
We have a junior single suite or a superior
double suite available for those dates.
What's the difference?
But junior suite is
smaller and has one twin
bed, well the superior suite
has a double bed and mini bar.
Okay, I would like to
reserve the superior suite.
Is breakfast included?
Yes, the buffet breakfast
is served every morning.
I will need your name
and your credit card
details in order to
complete the reservation.
Sure, my credit card number is...
Alright we're back so now let's
take a look at language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So we've got a lot of great phrases
and words today in language takeaway.
The first one that comes from the beginning
of the dialogue, it's availability.
Alright, so the woman wanted to
know if the hotel has availability.
So what does that mean?
That means do you have free rooms?
Do you have any rooms I could rent?
So instead of saying
do you have any free
rooms or do you have rooms available,
you can just say do you have availability?
That's right, so you're basically asking
the person do you have anything available?
So what's your availability?
Very good.
Okay, alright so we
asked the hotel if they
have availability and
obviously the receptionist
needs to know when
we expect to check in.
So this is a noun and
a verb but in today's
dialogue it's used as a verb so
it's something we do to check in.
So the person on the phone would like
to know what date you expect to check in.
That means when will
you arrive at our hotel?
That's right, so maybe
we will arrive to the city
a couple of days before
we check into the hotel.
So we really specifically want to know
when are you going to start sleeping here?
That's right, and the
opposite, so when you
leave the hotel is called
check out to check out.
That's right.
So we want to check
in on July 9th and the
receptionist tells us that we have
available a single suite or a double suite.
Alright, so these are two
different kinds of rooms.
Now a suite is different
from a room because
it actually means that
the space you're going
to use is more than one room,
maybe two rooms or three.
That's right, so it's a little bit
bigger than just a standard room.
You might have a sitting area or a
kitchen area, so that's what a suite is.
Very expensive rooms are suites as well.
They have a sitting area and a kitchen
and maybe even an extra bedroom.
That's right.
Okay, so we have a single
suite that means that we have
one of these big rooms
that is only for one person.
And a double suite means that
two or more people can sleep there.
That's right, so single will be one
person and double will be two people.
And we also heard
similar words with the beds
because sometimes the rooms aren't really
clear about what kind of beds they have.
So this person asked, "What's the
difference between these rooms?"
And the hotel employee answered,
"Well, the junior suite has one twin bed."
Alright, what's a twin bed?
So a twin bed is basically a bed that's
only for one person, only one person fits in
there.
Alright, so it's a single bed basically.
We call it a twin.
It's a standard size, so everywhere
you go, a twin is always for one person.
That's right.
Alright, and if you want to have another
person in bed, we have to get a bigger one.
And what's that bigger bed called?
It's called a double bed.
A double bed, so again,
double, double room, double bed.
So this means that two people
can sleep on the one bed.
That's right.
So this is important because sometimes you
want to book a hotel room, and it will be a
double suite, but it
will have two twin beds.
Alright, so it's a
double room, so it's for
two people, but each person
has their own small bed.
That's right.
Two twin beds.
Okay.
And lastly, the superior
double suite not only
had a double bed,
but also had a mini bar.
So you know what a
bar is, it's a place you
go to get some alcohol,
there's some drinks.
But a mini bar is a
little bit different, right?
It's a little refrigerator or a little area
where you will have snacks and drinks that
you can just basically take freely, but
obviously you will have to pay afterwards.
That's right.
So you can take them
when you're staying
there, but when you
check out, when you leave,
you have to pay for
everything you ate or drank.
That's right.
There's a lot of words
there on language
takeaway today, let's take a break
and listen to the dialogue again.
Madison, sweet, tell me I help you.
Yes, I am calling for Mexico.
I will be in town next week and would
like to know if you have availability.
Okay, ma'am, can you tell me
the date you expect to check in?
Yes, July 9th.
I will be there for seven nights.
Can you have a
junior single suite or a
superior double suite
available for those dates?
What's the difference?
The junior suite is
smaller and has one twin
bed, well the superior suite
has a double bed and mini bar.
Okay, I would like to
reserve the superior suite.
It's breakfast included?
Yes, the buffet breakfast
is served every morning.
I will need your name
and your credit card
details in order to
complete the reservation.
Sure, my credit card number is.
All right, so now it's
time for some phrases.
Let's start with fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
So the first phrase in fluency
builder might seem a little bit strange.
It's I will be in town next week.
I'll be in town in what town?
That's right.
If you say I will be in town, that
basically says I will be in this town.
I will be there.
I will be here.
So I'll be in the town you're in.
This is interesting.
So when I'm talking to someone, maybe
Marco is in Chicago and I'm in New York.
I call.
I say, hey Marco, I'll
be in town next week.
What are you doing?
Right.
You want to have a drink.
That means I'm going to be where?
You're going to be in Chicago.
That's right.
I'll be in Chicago like Marco is.
I'm not going to talk about where I am now.
This usually means I'm
going somewhere else.
That's right.
So actually you can
tell your friends that
you're going to be in
town or sometimes you have
to tell someone you're
going to be out of town.
I'll be out of town.
That means I won't be where I am now.
I won't be in New York.
I'll be somewhere else.
I'll be in Chicago.
That's right.
All right.
So now moving on where
when we were talking
specifically about the
hotel and maybe the what
is included with our suite, we
asked a very important question.
Is breakfast included
included in what in the price?
All right.
So this is a very common question like
you're saying Marco, but it's not obvious.
So when you ask is breakfast included, that
means do I have to pay extra for breakfast?
If breakfast is included,
I don't have to pay.
If it's not included, that means
I have to pay extra for breakfast.
That's right.
And in this case, breakfast is
included, but not just any breakfast.
It's a buffet breakfast.
My favorite kind of breakfast.
So this is pretty common with hotels.
They will serve a buffet breakfast
from 7am to 9am or whatever.
Buffet means that there's a room
with tables and food on the tables.
So you don't order food.
You just take whatever you want.
That's right.
So you can take whatever you
want and usually as much as you want.
That's the best part.
Okay.
So now we know that breakfast is included.
We know what a room is like.
So we're going to make
the reservation and the
hotel employees says
that he needs our credit
card details to
complete the reservation.
Credit card details.
Now you might be wondering what details.
Credit card details means the
specific information on your credit card.
So this is pretty common when you're making
a purchase on the phone or on the internet.
You have to enter.
You have to provide
your credit card details.
That means your name,
your credit card number
and the expiration date, which is
when the card will no longer be useful.
So it's necessary because obviously you can
say, yeah, I'm going to be there tomorrow
and then you don't
show up in the hotel loses
money so they need to make
sure that they have you somehow.
That's their way of protecting themselves.
They want to give you the room,
but they also don't want to lose money.
Okay.
So let's listen to our
dialogue one last time
and we'll be back to
talk a little bit more.
Madison, sweet, tell me I'll help you.
Yes.
I am calling for Mexico.
I will be in town next week and would
like to know if you have availability.
Okay, ma'am, can you tell me
the date you expect to check in?
Yes.
I will be there for seven nights.
We have a junior single suite or a superior
double suite available for those dates.
What's the difference?
The junior suite is smaller
and has one twin bed.
Well, the superior suite has
a double bed and mini bar.
Okay.
I would like to reserve the superior suite.
Is breakfast included?
Yes.
A buffet breakfast is served every morning.
I will need your name
and your credit card
details in order to
complete the reservation.
Sure.
My credit card number is...
All right, so talking
about hotels, I think
one of the most
important things out of this,
well, not important,
but also something that
you should know is that the
mini bar is always so expensive.
It is expensive.
Be very careful when you're
going into that mini bar.
Sometimes it seems like a really good idea.
You're hungry and there are
crackers or you want to beer.
But you have to look
at the menu because the
menu will have the prices
and maybe something
that's really cheap in a store
outside is really expensive at a hotel.
And I think sometimes,
I don't know, sometimes
it's even hard to
find that little menu.
So you don't even know what
the prices are, but you're so thirsty.
You just want to have something to
drink now and it ends up costing you $10.
That's why it's a be careful.
Any time you're in a hotel
room, expect the prices
to be pretty high for
the things in the hotel.
Unless of course
there's a sign or a piece
of paper that says that
something is free or complimentary.
Yeah, that's right.
Complimentary water is
very common in hotels.
They'll give you two free bottles of water.
That's right.
So complimentary means
you don't have to pay for it.
But if there's no sign,
then expect to pay a lot.
That's right.
Okay.
So if you guys have
any questions or any
doubts or you want to
suggest any other lesson
topic, you can visit
us at EnglishPod.com.
We'll hope to see you there.
Until next time.
Bye.